Guide to the Islamic Fundamentalist Audio Recordings Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Islamic fundamentalist audio recordings collection
1965-2000
MS 1880
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19.25
(1459 boxes)
The collection consists of audio recordings (in Arabic) of sermons, lectures, speeches, recitations of the Qur'?n (Koran) and poetry, interviews, radio broadcasts, and conversations, pertaining to Islam, in particular the fundamentalist perspective, and the Arab world. Over 200 speakers, primarily clerics, from over a dozen countries in the Middle East, Indian subcontinent, and Africa, are represented, documenting the views of a range of Jihadi, reformist, and moderate Islamic religious leaders. Only a few of the speakers are identified, including Osama bin Laden. The topics covered are wide-ranging and include the Qur'?n, Islamic jurisprudence, religious obligations and practices, mujahideen, Jihad, religious instruction, women, marriage, divorce, roles and responsibilities of husbands and wives, youth, death, extremism, secularism, evangelical Christians, Jewish people, and events and conflicts in the regions represented. The recordings date primarily from the 1980s to 2000, although some date from as early as the 1960s. The recordings are comprised of commercially-produced releases, copies of commercially-produced releases, and amateur recordings.
Custodial History
The recordings are thought to have originated in Osama bin Laden's compound in Kandah?r, Afghanistan. Following the Taliban's evacuation from Kandah?r on December 7, 2001, the audiocassettes were acquired by CNN. CNN transferred the materials to Williams College's Afghan Media Project, headed by anthropologist David Edwards, who later donated them to Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were a gift of David B. Edwards, 2006 and 2008.
Existence and Location of Copies
The collection is available in digital form through Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Other Finding Aids
An English/Arabic version of the finding aid is also available. See Guide to the Islamic Fundamentalist Audio Recordings Collection (English/Arabic).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played.
The entire collection has been digitized. Researchers must use the digital copies instead of the originals. Researchers wishing to access the digital copies or obtain a copy for their personal use should contact Manuscripts and Archives.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by repository assigned tape number.
General
This collection was described and digitized through the generous support of the Arcadia Foundation.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of audio recordings (in Arabic) of sermons, lectures, speeches, recitations of the Qur'?n (Koran) and poetry, interviews, radio broadcasts, and conversations, pertaining to Islam, in particular the fundamentalist perspective, and the Arab world. Over 200 speakers, primarily clerics, from over a dozen countries in the Middle East, Indian subcontinent, and Africa, are represented, documenting the views of a range of Jihadi, reformist, and moderate Islamic religious leaders. Only a few of the speakers are identified, including Osama bin Laden. The topics covered are wide-ranging and include the Qur'?n, Islamic jurisprudence, religious obligations and practices, mujahideen, Jihad, religious instruction, women, marriage, divorce, roles and responsibilities of husbands and wives, youth, death, extremism, secularism, evangelical Christians, Jewish people, and events and conflicts in the regions represented. The recordings date primarily from the 1980s to 2000, although some date from as early as the 1960s. The recordings are comprised of commercially-produced releases, copies of commercially-produced releases, and amateur recordings. Associated materials consist of inserts and photocopies of cassette casings.
Islam and politics; Islamic fundamentalism; Islamic sermons, Arabic; Jihad; Afghanistan -- Politics and government; Audiotapes
- Tape 1. Political situation in Algeria, Circa 1991-1992; 1 (Box 1)
  Summary (English)
  Side A. A speaker gives a lecture and Q&A on duty to fight in Algeria, likely soon after beginning of civil war in 1991. References to Islamic Salvation Front, Bush (unspecified), Muslim Brotherhood. Mostly in Modern Standard, sometimes in Palestinian Arabic. Audio cuts occasionally, but mostly intelligible.
  Side B. 0.00-18.00: Continuation of lecture on Side A. More specific information about weapons and training. 18.30 onwards: a different speaker recites Q 3:1-42.
  Summary (Arabic)
  ????? ?????. ??? ???????? (??? ?????). ?????? ?? ???? ?? ???? ?????? ?? ???????? ?? ??????? ??? ????? ????? ??????? ?? ??? 1991. ???? ?????? ????????? ??????? ? ??? (??? ????) ? ????? ??????? ????????. ?? ?????? ???????? ???????? ?? ??????????
  ????? ??????. ??? ???????? (??? ?????) ??????. 0.00- 18.00: ???? ??????. ??????? ????? ?? ?????? ?? ??????? ????????. ??? 18:30: ????? ???? ????? ???? ?????? ???? 1-42
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 2. The Islamic umma, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 2)
  Side A: A speaker gives a sermon in Modern Standard Arabic on or around the anniversary of Battle of Uhud. Subjects include West as enemy, the need for patience and persistence in Islam, the impending victory of Islam, corruption of Islamic thought by Sufism. Occasional gaps in audio.
  Side B: 0.00-3.00: Continuation of sermon on Side A. 8.30-14.30: A different speaker recites hadith and gives a sermon on the correct dress for men and women during prayer. 14.30-19.00: A different sermon by the same speaker on the requirement to face Mecca during prayer. 3.00-8.30: A different sermon by the same speaker on the corruption and misunderstanding of Islam by Muslims and the need to educate them in their religion.
  ????? ??????. ???? ????? ??????. 0?00- 3?00: ???? ??????. 3?00-8?30: ???? ????? ????? ?? ?????? ???? ??? ???????? ??????? ?????? ???????. 8?30-14?30: ???? ????? ????? ?? ?????? ?????? ?? ??????. ??? 14?30: ??? ?????? ????? ?? ???? ?????? ??? ??????
  ????? ??????.
  ???? ????? ??????. 0?00- 3?00: ???? ??????. 3?00-8?30: ???? ????? ????? ?? ?????? ???? ??? ???????? ??????? ?????? ???????. 8?30-14?30: ???? ????? ????? ?? ?????? ?????? ?? ??????. ??? 14?30: ??? ?????? ????? ?? ???? ?????? ??? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 3. The Islamic umma, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 3)
  Side A: A speaker gives a sermon in Modern Standard Arabic on the backwardness of the Islamic umma and the need for action to restore it to power. He discusses need for educational instutitions promoting pure Islam and for rich Muslims to finance Islamist projects.
  Side B: 0.00-5.00: Continuation of sermon on side A. 5.00-11.00: A different speaker gives a sermon on need for confrontation in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. 11.00 onwards: A third, unknown speaker gives a sermon on personal virtues needed for the victory of Islam.
  ????? ?????. ???? ?????. ???? ?? ???? ????? ????????? ??????? ????? ?????? ???????? ???????? ??? ???? ??? ??????? ??????
  ????? ??????. ???? ????? ??????. 0.00-5.00: ???? ??????. 5.00-11.00: ???? ?? ?????? ?? ???????? ?????? ??????. ??? 11.00: ???? ?? ????? ????? ???????? ????? ????? ?????
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 4. The Islamic umma, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 4)
  Side A. [Duplicate of Tape 3].
  Side B. [Duplicate of Tape 3].
  ????? ?????. ????? ????? 3
  ????? ??????. ????? ????? 3
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 5. The demands of Islam and Islamic law, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 5)
  Side A. A speaker gives a sermon in Modern Standard Arabic on piety. He discusses contemporary approaches to Islam among Muslims and criticizes flexibility and lack of commitment.
  Side B. 0.00-11.00: A speaker gives a general sermon on piety and the Day of Judgment. There are multiple breaks in audio, including a few seconds of conversation in colloquial Arabic at 8.08. 11.00-18.30: a recording of the following adhan and prayer. 18.30 onwards: a different, unknown speaker gives a sermon on the unacceptability of Muslim women seeing male doctors. The last minute of audio is unintelligible.
  ????? ?????. ???? ?????. ???? ??????? ?? ??????. ????? ??????? ??????? ?????? ??????? ???? ????????.
  ????? ??????. ???? ????? ??????. 0?00-11?00: ????? ????? ?? ?????? ???? ???????. 11?00-18?30: ????? ?????? ??????? ???????. ??? 18.30: ???? ??? ????? ?? ??? ???? ?????? ???????? ??? ????? ????. ??? ????? ?? ?????? ??? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 6. Relations with non-Muslims (sermon); live Quran recitation, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 6)
  Side A. 0.00-16.00: A speaker in Saudi Arabia gives a sermon on the relations between Muslims and non-Muslims. He refers to a recent loan made by Saudi Arabia to the Soviet Union (December 1990) as example of unacceptable relations. 16.00 onwards: a different speaker recites Q 9:1-44.
  Side B. A speaker recites Q 9:44-104 and 7:1-53.
  ????? ?????. ??? ?????? ?????? ??????. 0?00-16?00: ???? ?? ???????? ??? ???????? ???? ????????. ????? ?? ??? ?? ??????? ??????? ???????? ??? ??????? ????????? (?????? 1990) ????? ??????? ??? ??????. ??? 16.00: ????? ?? ???? ?????? ? ?????? 1-44.
  ????? ??????. ??? ?????? ?????? ??????. ????? ?? ???? ?????? ? ?????? 44-104 ????? ???????? ?????? 1-53.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 7. Qur?a?n recitation, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 7)
  Side A. A speaker recites Q 10:102-109, 11, and 12:1-79.
  Side B. 0.00-5.30: Continuation of Q 12. 5.30 onwards: a different speaker recites Q 13, 14, 15, and 16:1-55
  ????? ?????. ??? ?????? ??????. ????? ?? ??? ???? ? ??? ? ????.
  ????? ??????. ??? ?????? ?????? ??????. ????? ?? ??? ????? ? ??????? ? ????? ? ?????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 8. Sermons by various speakers, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 8)
  Side A. 0.00-22.00: A speaker recites a prayer near the end of Ramadan. A large crowd responds with "amen" after each sentence. 22.00-30.00: A different speaker reads a letter from women in a (possibly Syrian) prison, published in a Kuwaiti magazine, describing prison conditions and torture. He urges Muslims to act, especially by donating money, and prays for the destruction of their oppressors. 30.00 onwards: A different speaker gives a sermon on da'wa.
  Side B. 0.00-8.00: Continuation of sermon at the end of side A. 8.00-13.30: A different speaker gives a sermon on piety. 13.30-23.00: A different speaker gives another sermon on piety. 23.00-29.00: A different speaker gives another sermon. Circa 28.10, the volume drops and fragments of conversation in colloquial Arabic are heard over the original audio. 29.00 onward: A different speaker recites Q 19:1-10.
  ????? ?????. ??? ?????? ?????? ??????. ?.?? ‎- ??.??: ???? ???? ???? ??? ????? ??? ?????? ??? ?????? ?? ???? ?????. ??.?? ‎- ??.??: ???? ??? ???? ????? ?? ???? ?? ?????? ?? ????? ?? ??????? ? ??? ???????? ??? ????? ? ?????? ??????. ??? ?????: ???? ??? ????? ?? ??????
  ????? ??????. ??? ?????? ?????? ??????. ?.?? ‎- ?.??: ???? ?????? ??? ?????? ?????. ?.?? ‎- ??.??: ???? ??? ?????? ?? ???? ??? ???????. ??? ?????: ????? ???? ????? ???? ? ‎- ??.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 9. Qur?a?n recitation, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 9)
  Side A. A speaker introduces the contents of the tape. It is part of a complete recording of the Quran undertaken by an Islamic recording company, Tasjeelat Uhud, made at tarawih prayers by five different imams. This tape is of al-Tubaykhi. Recitation begins at 2.30 and covers Q: 8 - 9:30.
  Side B. Recitation of Q 9:30-129.
  ????? ?????. ???? ?? ??? ?????? ???????. ?????? ??? ?? ????? ???? ?????? ?? ??? ??????? ???. ????? ???? ??????? ????? ? ‎- ?? ?? ???? ??????.
  ????? ??????. ???? ?? ??? ?????? ???????. ????? ???? ???? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 10. Women's ethics (lecture), Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 10)
  Side A. A speaker introduces a lecture by al-'Id on women's ethics. Al-'Id is a lecturer at a shari'a department (unspecified). Quran recitation and some conversation are audible in the background. The end of side A is announced.
  Side B. 0.00-34.00: Continuation of lecture on side A. A speaker announces the end of the tape and the beginning of additional material. 34.00 onward: different speakers recite religious poetry, prayers, and advice for the Muslim listener.
  ????? ?????. ??? ?? ???? ?????. ?????? ?? ????????? ? ???????? ?????? ?? ??? ?? ???? ?????? ????? ?? ???? ???? ?????? ??? ??????? ? ??????? ????????.
  ????? ??????. ??? ?? ???? ????? ??????. ???? ????????. ??? ???? ?????? ????? ??????? ? ????? ? ????? ???? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 11. The headscarf (hijab) and other women's issues, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 11)
  Side A. A speaker gives a sermon in colloquial Egyptian Arabic on hijab and other women's issues. Audio quality is poor and some segments are unintelligible. Some unintelligible fragments of Quran and conversation are audible at the beginning and end of the tape.
  Side B. A speaker gives a sermon in a mixure of colloquial Egyptian Arabic and Modern Standard Arabic on women's issues. Audio quality is poor and some segments are unintelligible. Some unintelligible fragments of Quran and conversation are audible at the beginning and end of the tape.
  ????? ?????. ???? ???????? ??????? ?? ?????? ?????? ??????. ????? ??? ???? ???? ??????? ??? ??????.
  ????? ??????. ???? ???????? ??????? ?? ????? ??????. ????? ??? ???? ???? ??????? ??? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 12. Qur?a?n recitation, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 12)
  Side A. A speaker recites Q 45:20 - 48:29.
  Side B. Identical to Side A. A speaker recites Q 45:20 - 48:29.
  ????? ?????. ????? ??? ??????? ???????? ????? ??????.
  ????? ??????. ????? ??? ??????? ???????? ????? ??????
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 13. Qur?a?n recitation, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 13)
  Side A. A speaker recites Q 41:47 - 43:70.
  Side B. A speaker recites Q 43:59 - 45:37.
  ????? ?????. ????? ??? ???? ? ?????? ? ??????.
  ????? ??????. ????? ????? ?????? ????????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 14. Piety and taqwa, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 14)
  Side A. 0.00-1.45: a fragment of the introduction to a lecture. 1.45 onwards: a different speaker gives a lecture on piety.
  Side B. Continuation of side A.
  ????? ?????. ???? ?? ???????..
  ????? ??????. ????? ?????? ?????..
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 15. Ramadan prayers and hadith, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 15)
  Side A. Different speakers recite Ramadan prayers and hadith. The tape ends with an announcement from Tasjilat Uhud, an Islamic recording company.
  Side B. Different speakers recite Ramadan prayers and hadith. Side B ends with "this is the middle of the tape". Sides A and B are likely reversed.
  ????? ?????. ????? ???? ? ????? ?? ????? ?????. ?? ??????? ???
  ????? ??????. ????? ???? ? ????? ?? ????? ?????. ?? ??????? ???
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 16. Islamic law and the Egyptian government, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 16)
  Side A. A speaker gives a lecture on the superiority of shari'a to manmade law. He discusses the Egyptian government and its suppression of the Muslim Brotherhood. The speaker is a member who is currently confined to al-Fayyoum. He urges listeners to take immediate action toward Islamic rule. The date of the lecture can be estimated from remarks on actions taken by the government in 1988 and a reference to the current suppression of Sheikh Abdul Hamid Kishk, who died in 1996.
  Side B. A speaker introduces a lecture by Umar [unintelligible] Abd al-Rahman in response to a decision issued by al-Azhar on January 1st (year unknown). The lecture argues that submission to any law but sharia is tantamount to apostasy.
  ????? ?????. ????? ???? ?????? ?? ???? ??????? ??? ??????? ??????. ????? ??????? ??????? ?????? ?????? ??????? ????????. ??????? ?? ??? ?? ??????? ????? ?? ??? ??????. ??? ????????? ??? ????? ??????? ????? ??? ????? ???????? ? ??? ?????? ?????? ????????. ???? ????? ????? ???????? ?? ??????? ?? ??????? ?????? ?? ??? 1988 ??? ??? ??????? ????? ???? ??? ???? ???? ?? ??? 1996.
  ????? ??????. ??? ??? ??????. ?????? ?? ??????? ???????? ?? ??? ??? ?????? (????? ?????? ??? ?????) ?? ???? ????? ?????? ?? 1 ????? (????? ??? ??????).
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 17. Jihad in hadith, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 17)
  Side A. A speaker recites hadith, mostly on the topics of martyrdom and jihad. Audio quality is poor, but recitation is intelligible.
  Side B. A speaker recites hadith, mostly on the topics of martyrdom and jihad. Audio quality is poor, but recitation is intelligible.
  ????? ?????. ????? ?? ?????? ?? ??????? ???????.
  ????? ??????. ????? ?? ?????? ?? ??????? ???????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 18. Lecture and Q&A on miscellaneous topics, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 18)
  Side A. A speaker gives a lecture and answers questions on various questions of faith and Islamic law. The lecture is in Modern Standard Arabic with many interjections in Saudi or Gulf Arabic. Audio quality is medium: some short sections are unintelligible; significant background noise (children, etc.).
  Side B. 0.00-11.00: Continuation of lecture and Q&A. A different speaker announces the end of the tape, produced by Tasjeelat Makka al-Mukarrama. 11.00 onwards: the same speaker gives a different lecture and Q&A on various topics.
  ????? ?????. ????? ???? ?????? ????? ?? ????? ???? ????? ?????? ?? ??????? ???????? ?????????. ???????? ??????? ?? ??????? ???????? ????????. ???? ????? ??????: ??? ??????? ??? ??????.????? ?????. ????? ???? ?????? ????? ?? ????? ???? ????? ?????? ?? ??????? ???????? ?????????. ???????? ??????? ?? ??????? ???????? ????????. ???? ????? ??????: ??? ??????? ??? ??????.
  ????? ??????. ???? ???????? ????????. ????? ?????? ???? ????? ?????? ?? ????? ??????? ??? ???????. ??? ??.??: ?????? ?????? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 19. Qur?a?n recitation, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 19)
  Side A. A speaker reads Q 112 and Q 1:1-5.
  Side B. A speaker gives a general lecture on usul al-din and takes questions from the audience. Mostly in Modern Standard Arabic, sometimes in colloquial Egyptian Arabic.
  ????? ?????. ????? ???? ??????? ? ??? ???? ?? ???? ??????.
  ????? ??????. ?????? ???? ?? ???? ????? ? ????? ????? ??????.????? ???????? ?????? ???????? ???????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 20. Topics in hadith, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 20)
  Side A. A speaker gives a lecture on various topics in hadith, including food, dress, jewelry, ablution, piety, and women's rights.
  ????? ?????. ?????? ??? ?????? ?????? ?? ?????? ? ??? ?? ??? ?????? ?????? ??????? ??????? ? ?????????? ? ???????? ??????? ? ????? ??????.
  ????? ??????. ???? ????????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 21. Q&A on miscellaneous topics, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 21)
  Side A. A speaker answers questions from the audience about Islamic law in everyday life.
  Side B. 0.00-14.30: Continuation of Q&A. 14.30 onwards: a different speaker gives a lecture and Q&A on various topics.
  ????? ?????. ????? ???? ??? ????? ??????? ??? ??????? ????????? ?? ?????? ???????.
  ????? ??????. ???? ???????. ??? ?????: ?????? ???? ?? ????? ??? ? ????? ?? ??????? ?? ?????? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 22. Islamic hygiene, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 22)
  Side A. A speaker gives a sermon on Islamic hygiene.
  Side B. 0.00-28.00: Continuation of lecture on side A. 28.00 onwards: A speaker announces the end of the tape and the following recitation of Quran 43 and 44 by Mahmud Khalil al-Husari.
  ????? ?????. ?????? ?? ??????? ??????? ?? ???????..
  ????? ??????. ???? ????????. ??? ??.??: ????? ??? ?????? ??????? ?? ????? ???? ??????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 23. Q&A on miscellaneous topics, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 23)
  Side A. A speaker answers questions from the audience about Islamic law. Audio is faint, but intelligible.
  ????? ?????. ????? ???? ??? ????? ??????? ??? ??????? ?????????..
  - Preservation masters, 1
  - Use copies, 1
- Tape 24. Qur?a?n recitation; Government and the Muslim Brotherhood, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 24)
  Side A. A speaker recites Q 43:55-65, 44:37-59, and 4:66-72. Circa 5.15, a different speaker gives a speech to and chants Islamic slogans with a large crowd. He urges listeners to follow God's law and not fear the Egyptian government. He makes several references to incarcerated Brothers.
  ????? ?????. ????? ?? ??? ?????? ??????? ???????. ??? 5.20: ???? ?? ????? ????? ?? ??????? ???????? ?? ????? ???? ???? ???? ????? ?? ??????? ???????.
  ????? ??????. ????? ?????? ?????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 26. Egypt, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 26)
  Side A. Continuation of lecture on side B. Circa 23.00, a different speaker reads Qutb and lectures on the same subject. A speaker announces the date and publisher (Jama'at al-jihad) at the end of the tape.
  Side B. A speaker announces the tape as part of a series of publications by Jama'at al-jihad on jihad in Egypt. He describes the actions of the Egyptian government as apostasy and encourages Islamist agitation. He makes several references to the Muslim Brotherhood and other Islamist groups.
  ????? ?????. ???? ???????? ??? ?????? ?????. ??? 23.00: ?????? ???? ?? ??? ???????. ???? ?????? ?????? ??????? ???? ??????? (????? ??????).
  ????? ??????. ???? ?? ????? ?????? ?? ??? ?????? ??? ?????? ?? ??? ???? ?????? ?? ???????? ????? ?????????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 27. Political strategy in Islamic history, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 27)
  Side A. A speaker announces a lecture by al-'Ubaydi, a professor at al-Imam Muhammad bin S'ud University, as part of a book festival in al-Riyadh. The lecture is titled "Factors of Victory and Defeat throughout Islamic History" and describes the personal and political virtues and strategies necessary for success and victory. The date of the lecture is announced as Wednesday, 23 Rabi' al-Awwal of the year "one thousand, four hundred, and one thousand" of the Hijri calendar, presumably a mistake. Assuming 1400 as a starting point, there are five possibilities within the date range of the collection: 12/28/83, 11/26/86, 10/2/91, 8/31/94, and 7/3/99.
  Side B. Continuation of lecture on Side A.
  ????? ?????. ???? ???????. ??? ????? ?? ????? ?????? ???? ?? ????. ???????? ??? ?? ?????? ?????? ?? ??????. ??? ?????? "????? ????? ???????? ??? ??????? ????????"? ???? ??????? ?????????????? ??????? ????????? ??????? ?????. ???????? ??? ???????? 23 ?? ???? ????? ?? ????? "??? ????? ??? ????" ??????. ?? ??????? ??? ?? ???????? ???? ???? ???????? ?????? ???????? ??? ???? ?????? ????????: 28/12/83 ? 26/11/86 ? 2/10/91 ? 31/8/94 ? ?3/7/99.
  ????? ??????. ???? ???????. ???? ????????.
  - Preservation masters, 2
  - Use copies, 2
- Tape 28. Sexual relations, zina, and marriage, Circa 1965-2000; 1 (Box 28)
  Side A. Following the adhan, a speaker gives a sermon (likely a Friday sermon) in MSA on zina. He recites the relevant texts and suggests remedies for what he perceives as a widespread social malady. The tape ends with a general prayer, a crowd responding with "Amen" after each phrase, and cuts in mid-sentence.
  Side B. The same speaker on side A gives a different sermon on the importance of regular prayer.
  ????? ?????. ??? ?????? ? ???? ??????? ?? ????? ? ??? ??????? ?????? ????????.????? ?????? ????? ?? ??????.99.